# **ZHENGYANG HUANG**

- email: zhuang0buo@outlook.com - phone: +1 757-719-6047

- project highlights: https://zhengyang-huang.me/Project-Highlights.pdf

- website: <a href="https://zhengyang-huang.me/">https://zhengyang-huang.me/</a>

- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/zhengyang-huang/

Zhengyang is a new media artist working in interactive media with web and game engine as well as 3D/2D graphics, motion effects, and videography. He's been doing both collaborative and self-initiated projects for years and gained versatile experiences in aesthetics, software and skills spanning from artistic, educational to commercial fields.

## **EDUCATION**

UCLA - MFA, Design | Media Arts - Los Angeles, CA College of William and Mary - BA, Studio Arts - 3D - Williamsburg, VA June 2021 May 2019

### **SKILL**

- Web and Game Interactives: HTML, Javascript, CSS, JQuery, Wordpress, Webpack, Adobe XD, Unity3D, Unity C#, Processing, Arduino, Git, Github;
- 3D/2D Graphics: Blender, Maya, VR video, Reality Capture, R3D Wrap, RunwayML, Adobe Illustrator, Substance Painter, Photoshop, InDesign, Figma;
- Videography and Motion Graphics: Adobe
   AfterEffects, Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe Audition,
   Audacity;
- Soft Skills: Concept building, Communication Skill, Teamwork, Problem-Solving Ability, Flexibility, Time Management;

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Freelance Web Design/Development - Kindred Spirit

Feb 2022 - Present

- Brainstorm and bring ideas with different iterations for website improvements;
- Redesign user flow and create web prototypes with Adobe Creative Suite and Blender;
- Improve web page layouts and create new interactions, images and web assets with customized HTML/CSS on Squarespace;

# Videographer / Visual Designer - Global Talent Link · Contract

August 2021 - Present

- Conceptualized brand images and stories, created prototypes and creative assets, and revamped company website pages on Wordpress;
- Designed landing page and header with Lottie SVG animation and responsive features, developed in HTML, CSS,
   Javascript;
- Creating a marketing video with animated assets, motion effects, company footages;
- Collaborated with service and development team for a innovative, clear and meaningful company representation;
- Illustrated community flyer to be produced both in print and online, with QR code tracking included for marketing purpose;

# Lecturer - UCLA - Los Angeles, CA

June 2021 - August 2021

- Taught *DESMA 24 Motion* (<a href="https://classes.dma.ucla.edu/Summer21/24/">https://classes.dma.ucla.edu/Summer21/24/</a>), a course in theory and practice of motion graphics including video making and editing, 3D modeling and animation, as well as GAN generated images;
- Led learning sessions and made tutorials for Autodesk Maya, Adobe After Effects, Premiere Pro, and RunwayML;
- Led lectures, discussions, screenings, critiques to expand knowledge and develop critical thinking on moving images;

# Teaching assistant - UCLA - Los Angeles, CA

October 2019 - June 2021

- Led discussion sessions to expand course materials and have more discussions on media art history and practice;
- Designed and created websites to manage and share materials and resources as well as showcasing student work;

- Assisted instructors in and out of class, coordinated meetings, supported students on projects and assignments;
- List of courses:
  - o 09/2019 12/2019 Media Arts Introduction
  - o 01/2020 03/2020 Motion (https://classes.dma.ucla.edu/Winter20/24/)
  - o 09/2020 12/2020 Special Topics: Cultural Appropriation With Machine Learning
  - o 09/2020 12/2020 Design Culture
  - o 01/2021 03/2021 Motion
  - o 03/2021 06/2021 Video (https://classes.dma.ucla.edu/Spring21/153/)

# **EXHIBITION**

# 2021

- *Air, Water, Fire*, SLSA 2021 (Society for Literature, Science, and The Arts,), Penny W. Stamps School of Art & Design at the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, <a href="https://stamps.umich.edu/events/slsa-exhibit">https://stamps.umich.edu/events/slsa-exhibit</a>, 10/2021
- *Air, Water, Fire*, in group show *The Last Online Show*, D|MA MFA show, http://projects.dma.ucla.edu/exhibitions/mfa2021/2020/10/13/zhengyang/, 05/2021
- Air, solo show in collaboration, online, D|MA, 02/2021

#### 2020

- Share Screen, D|MA Fall Preview Show, <a href="https://projects.dma.ucla.edu/exhibitions/sharescreen/">https://projects.dma.ucla.edu/exhibitions/sharescreen/</a>, 10/2020
  - Besides showing work, I also developed and designed the landing page of the exhibition website

#### 2019

- Image at Surface, solo show at Linda Matney Gallery, Williamsburg VA, 04/2019
- Capstone Show, group show at Williamsburg Contemporary Art Center, Williamsburg VA, 02/2019
- A Sense of Occasion, group show at Andrews Gallery, Williamsburg VA, 05/2019

### 2018

• Transposition: Asian Cultures, group show at Linda Matney Gallery, Williamsburg VA, 02/2018

# **PUBLICATION**

- Image at Surface, Artsy, 2019
- Transparency, Acropolis Art Journal, 2017
- Solidarity, Acropolis Art Journal, 2017
- Chaos // Disorder, Acropolis Art Journal, 2016

### **GRANTS AND AWARDS**

#### 2021

- Clifton Webb Scholarship, School of Arts & Architecture, UCLA, 01/2021 06/2021
- Dr. Hyuman Eugene Oxman & Frieda Dreyer Oxman Fellowship Fund, School of Arts & Architecture, UCLA, 01/2021
   06/2021

#### 2020

2019

• Dean's Graduate Scholarship, D|MA, School of Arts & Architecture, UCLA, 09/2020 - 06/2021

• Alumni Association Award, College of William and Mary, 06/2019

## 2018

- Honors Research Project Fellowship, College of William and Mary, 08/2018 05/2019
- The Joseph Palin Thorley Memorial Scholarship for the Study of Art, College of William and Mary
- Initiated as a member of Phi Beta Kappa, Alpha of Virginia at the College of William and Mary, 12/05/2018 2017
- The Joseph Palin Thorley Memorial Scholarship for the Study of Art, College of William and Mary
- Roy R. Charles Grant for Semester Independent Study, College of William and Mary